wotnews.com.au 2012-05-24

# Wotnews Privacy Policy

wotnews.com.au (Wotnews) knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. We are committed to protecting the privacy and security of any personally identifiable information you provide us. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By visiting the Wotnews website, you are accepting the practices outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

Wotnews has created this privacy statement ("Statement") in order to demonstrate our commitment to the privacy of our customers. Privacy on the wotnews.com.au web site (the "Site") is of great importance to us. Because we gather important information from our visitors and customers, we have established this Statement as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices. 

##### Changes to this policy

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Policy changes). Each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date, and we will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive. 

##### What does the policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers Wotnews' treatment of personal information that Wotnews gathers when you are on the Wotnews website and when you use Wotnews services.

This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Wotnews does not own or control, or to individuals that Wotnews does not employ or manage. 

##### What personal information about users does Wotnews collect?

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a friendly, customised, and efficient experience. We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website. We do not process this information in a way that is incompatible with the purpose for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you. We collect the following types of information from our users: 

##### Information you provide to us

We receive and store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of the site's features. The personal information you provide is used for such purposes as: 

  * Registration: In order for you to use Wotnews services, such as publishing your own news to the website, you must complete a registration form. As part of this registration form, we require your name and email address. 

##### Automatic information

  * Wotnews uses cookies (See Cookies section below) and other technologies to enhance your online experience and to learn about how you use the website in order to improve the quality of our services. 
  * Wotnews' servers automatically record traffic data when you visit our website, including the URL, IP address, browser type and language, page requested and the date and time of your request. Wotnews uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website. 
  * Wotnews may also record and display, on any page, the total counts a given page has been viewed so as to indicate to users the popularity of the content. 

##### Cookies

Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our website are visited and by how many people. 

The "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of Wotnews' most attractive features. 

##### Email communications

Providing your email address is not a spam risk. Above all, we respect your privacy. Wotnews will never provide your email address to a third party without your explicit permission, as detailed in the "Sharing Your Information" section below. 

The only emails you will ever receive from us are:

  * an initial verification email to activate your account 
  * password reminders upon request 
  * notices of critical server updates that may interrupt our service 
  * your personalised Wotnews daily email news report 
  * occasionally we ask our users for input and feedback on our service to help us make improvements 
  * updates about improvements to our service or about new offerings 
  * 'share with a friend' or 'refer a friend' emails (performed on the site) sent by other users of the Wotnews website 
  * OR...if you send us a question by email and would like to hear back from us 

##### Sharing your information

We neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone. We share your personal information only as described below. 

  * **Wotnews personnel:** Wotnews personnel (including, for the avoidance of doubt, consultants and/or contractors) may have access to user information while carrying out their duties in the normal course of Wotnews business. 
  * **Business transfers:** In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Wotnews, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. 
  * **Protection of Wotnews and others:** We may release personal information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with that law; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Wotnews, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 
  * **Syndication:** Wotnews allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the website. 
  * **With your consent:** Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your personal information may be shared with third parties or used for a purpose incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected, and you will be able to prevent the sharing of this information by opting out. 

##### Sharing your information

  * Your Wotnews account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need to work to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer. 
  * Only employees who need personal information to perform a specific job (for example, a customer service representative) are granted access to it. All of our employees are kept up to date on our privacy and security practices. 

##### Access and control of your personal information

You can access your personal information on our website and correct, amend, or delete information that is inaccurate. Upon logging in visit the user profile settings area located at: Edit Profile. 

##### Your choices

  * You can opt not to disclose information, but then you may be unable to use certain features on our website, such as publishing your organisation's news or personalising your news profile. 
  * By visiting the 'edit profile' of the Wotnews website, you can correct, amend, add or delete personal information stored on the site. 
  * You may request deletion of your Wotnews account by emailing us at support@wotnews.com.au. 
  * As explained earlier, the "help" portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. Please note, however, that if your browser does not accept cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of some of our attractive features. 

##### Can children use Wotnews' services?

You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Wotnews website. As a result, Wotnews does not specifically collect information about children. We recommend that minors between the ages of 13 and 18 ask and receive their parents' permission before using Wotnews or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet. 

##### Conditions of use

If you decide to visit Wotnews website, your visit and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of Queensland state law. 

##### Effective date of this privacy policy

This Privacy Policy is effective as of 1 September, 2007 and was last updated on 12 December 2007.
